Guide to the Edward Luther Stevenson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edward Luther Stevenson papers
1859-1944
GEN MSS 1517
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20
(55 boxes)
The papers include correspondence, writings, lectures, notes, research material, and memorabilia documenting the personal life and professional career of Edward Luther Stevenson. The papers relate to Stevenson's studies at Franklin College and the University of Heidelberg, his teaching in public schools, his professorship at Rutgers University, his service to the Hispanic Society of America, and his numerous lectures and publications on the discovery and exploration of the New World. Highlighted in the papers are Stevenson's cartographic research and his efforts to collect, copy, and publish historic maps.
Stevenson, Edward Luther, 1858-1944
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Manuscripts and Archives, 2018.
Gift of Edward L. Stevenson, Jr., and Mrs. Harvey W. Bell, 1946.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1859-1944. II. Writings, 1907-1941. III. Subject Files, 1870-1941.
Scope and Contents
The Edward Luther Stevenson Papers consist of correspondence, writings, lectures, notes, research material, and memorabilia, which document Stevenson's personal life and professional career as an historian, teacher, cartographer, lecturer, and author. The papers relate to Stevenson's studies at Franklin College (Franklin, Indiana) and the University of Heidelberg, his public school teaching in Indiana and Illinois, his professorship in history at Rutgers University, his service to the Hispanic Society of America, and his numerous lectures and publications on the discovery and exploration of the New World. Highlighted in the papers are Stevenson's cartographic research and efforts to collect, copy, and publish historic maps.
Edward L. Stevenson, Jr. and Katharine Stevenson Bell donated their father's papers to the Yale University Library in 1946. Stevenson's collection of maps and glass slides is located in the Map Collection of the Sterling Memorial Library. The remainder of the donation comprises the Stevenson Papers in the Manuscripts and Archives Department. These papers are arranged in three series: I. Correspondence, 1859-1944; Series II. Writings, 1907-1941; Series III. Subject Files, 1870-1941.
Series I contains the bulk of Stevenson's correspondence. Series II. includes the majority of Stevenson's book manuscripts, while Series III is composed of additional manuscripts for Stevenson's writings and lectures, notes, research material, teaching materials, and memorabilia.
The arrangment of correspondence in Series I reflects Stevenson's groupings of his incoming and outgoing letters. The series is arranged in three sections. Letters are roughly divided by topic ( Topical), others are in chronological order ( Chronological), and in the largest section Alphabetical, correspondence is arranged alphabetically within several rough time spans. In the latter section the time spans are broadly defined and ranges of dates overlap. In the series, therefore, correspondence of an individual or organization for any given date on any specified topic may appear in all three sections and in more than one place in the Alphabetical section.
The correspondence spans the entire length of Stevenson's life, though the earliest items in the papers are letters relating to Stevenson's wife's family, the Runyons of New Brunswick, New Jersey. Stevenson's letters begin in 1876 while he was attending Franklin College and participating in activities of Phi Delta Theta fraternity. Early letters trace Stevenson's career as a teacher in Rising Sun, Indiana, and a superintendent of schools in Gilman (Iroquois County), Illinois. His correspondents include college faculty and friends and fellow teachers. These correspondents continue to write Stevenson during his graduate studies at Johns Hopkins University and at the University of Heidelberg.
The correspondence includes letters concerning Rutgers University during the twenty years Stevenson served on the faculty, as well as. letters relating to Stevenson's participation in several professional organizations such as the American Historical Association and the American Geographical Society. The majority of the correspondence, however, relates to Stevenson's efforts to acquire, reproduce, and publish maps. Correspondents include librarians such as Victor Paltsits, fellow map scholars including Jean Henry Vignaud, booksellers, representatives of scholarly societies, diplomats, and publisher's representatives.
The correspondence also documents Stevenson's relations with the Hispanic Society of America, which Stevenson joined in 1904. He published many of his cartographic studies under the auspices of this society. There are numerous exchanges with Archer M. Huntington, president of the Hispanic Society, and other society officers and members.
Other correspondence concerns Stevenson's service as a member of the New Jersey Commission on the Jamestown Tercentennial Exposition; arrangements for his numerous public lectures and for his lecture series at Johns Hopkins University, the University of California, and King's College, London; and travel and schedules for his 1925 trip to Egypt as a delegate to the International Geographic Congress. Scattered throughout the correspondence are letters concerning Stevenson's siblings and children and his home in Yonkers, New York. Some correspondence in 1930s and 1940s contains information about Stevenson's forebears, and exchanges with Florence A. Patterson and others contain reminiscences of Stevenson's boyhood in Rozetta (Henderson County), Illinois and education at Franklin College.
Series II, WRITINGS, is composed of materials relating to Stevenson's books and articles. For any particular title there may be relevant correspondence, research material, notes, drafts, handwritten and typed copies of the manuscript, proofs, illustrative material, prints, and reviews. For the Derrotero of Alonso de Chaves. There are also photostatic copies of the original text. Titles in the listing for Series II are in abbreviated form. Stevenson's compilation of typescript copies of title pages to his works (folders 569-570, 574) are helpful in identifying individual book titles in Series II and lectures, articles, book reviews, and other miscellaneous writings included in Series III.
The nine sections in which materials in Series III are arranged reflect the variety of papers contained in SUBJECT FILES. Addresses and Lectures includes manuscripts for Stevenson's public lectures, lecture series, individual addresses, and classroom lectures. A title listed in quotation marks indicates a title copied from the manuscript. Other titles are descriptive of the subject matter. Several of the lectures on French and European history were probably given for the Rutgers College Extension. Similar materials are found in the Manuscripts section, which also includes drafts of articles and papers presented to the Yonkers' Fortnightly Club for the Study of Anthropology. Handwritten and printed copies of book reviews by Stevenson are in folders 395 and 396, while the section Printed Material includes some printed copies of Stevenson's writings, publicity for his lectures and publications, and some bibliographic lists. The sections of Notes and Outlines contain Stevenson's research materials for courses he taught while at Rutgers as well as for his investigations of the history of cartography and the significance of maps to the discovery and exploration of the New World.
The section Personal Papers contains material on Stevenson's college and early teaching career. Folder 398 includes Stevenson's diary as a student at Franklin College, while folder 400 contains articles written by Stevenson as an undergraduate. Numerous pieces of Illinois and Indiana memorabilia, such as invitations, programs, brochures, clippings, menus, reports, and exams are included in folders 410-414 along with later contracts, notes, bills, travel souvenirs, membership certificates, and greeting cards. Folder 403 contains notebooks, apparently dating from Stevenson's graduate studies. Additional notebooks and papers from his doctoral studies in Germany are arranged in the section Student Papers. The final section in the papers Miscellanea is composed of additional research materials, illustrative materials for publications and lectures, and compilations for bibliographies of Stevenson's works.
Edward Luther Stevenson
Edward Luther Stevenson was born in Rozetta, Illinois in 1858. He received A.B. and A.M. degrees from Franklin College (1881, 1884) and was an educator in the public schools of Indiana and Illinois from 1881 to 1887. He studied history and political economy at Johns Hopkins University from 1887 to 1888 and received a Ph.D. from the University of Heidelberg in 1890. From 1891 until 1911 Stevenson taught history at Rutgers University and from 1910 on he served the Hispanic Society of America. Stevenson wrote and lectured widely on cartography and the discovery and exploration of the New World. He died in Yonkers, New York in 1944.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Cartography -- History; Historical geography -- Maps; Geography; History -- Study and teaching; Maps -- Reproduction; Henderson County (Ill.); Iroquois County (Ill.); Rising Sun (Ind.); Cartographers; Historians; Chaves, Alonso de, d. 1599; Huntington, Archer M. (Archer Milton), 1870-1955; Paltsits, Victor Hugo, 1867-1952; Runyon, Elias; Stevenson, Edward Luther, 1858-1944; American Geographical Society of New York; Franklin College (Franklin, Ind.); Hispanic Society of America; Rutgers University -- Faculty; Universität Heidelberg; International Geographical Congress (11th) -- Cairo, Egypt -- 1925
- Correspondence, 1859-1944; Series I; 8; (26 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains files arranged in three sections: Alphabetical, Chronological, and Topical.
  - Alphabetical
    - A - Z, 1891-1893 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - A - Z, 1893-1896, 1901-1903 (Box 2, Folder 8-19)
    - A - L; miscellaneous, 1903-1907 (Box 3, Folder 20-27)
    - A - M, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - A - Z, 1910-1923 (Box 4, Folder 29-36)
    - A - Z; miscellaneous, 1913-1914 (Box 5, Folder 37-41)
    - A - Z; miscellaneous, 1915-1916 (Box 6, Folder 42-54)
    - A - S, 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 55-66)
    - A - Z, 1917-1929 (Box 8, Folder 67-72)
    - A - Z, 1919-1923 (Box 9, Folder 73-83)
    - A - S, 1923-1924 (Box 10, Folder 84-96)
    - A - Z, 1925-1928 (Box 11, Folder 97-107)
    - A - Z, 1926-1929 (Box 12, Folder 108-120)
    - A - Z; miscellaneous, 1926-1933 (Box 13, Folder 121-126)
    - A - Z, 1928-1932 (Box 14, Folder 127-137)
    - A - Z, 1931-1934 (Box 15, Folder 138-145)
    - A - R, 1932-1933 (Box 16, Folder 146-153)
    - A - Z, 1935. (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - A - Z; miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 155-160)
    - A - M, 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 161-165)
    - A - Z; n.d., 1937-1942 (Box 17, Folder 166-172)
  - Chronological
    - 1859-1902 (Box 18, Folder 173-185)
    - 1903-1919 (Box 19, Folder 186-200)
    - 1920-1927 (Box 20, Folder 201-114)
    - 1928-1934 (Box 21, Folder 215-223)
    - 1935-1941 (Box 22, Folder 224-235)
    - 1942, 1944, undated (Box 23, Folder 236-239)
  - Topical
    - Egypt, 1924-1935 (Box 24, Folder 240)
    - Germany, 1926-1933 (Box 24, Folder 241)
    - Hispanic Society of America, 1904-1936, n. d. (Box 24, Folder 242-246)
    - International Geographic Congress, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 247)
    - Italy, 1924-1934 (Box 24, Folder 248-249)
    - Jamestown Exposition, 1906-1907 (Box 24, Folder 250)
    - Newberry Library, 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 251)
    - Paltsits, Victor Hugo, 1904-1921 (Box 25, Folder 252-253)
    - Patterson, Florence A., 1935-1936 (Box 25, Folder 254)
    - Publications, 1901-1926 (Box 25, Folder 255)
    - Rutgers University, 1938-1941 (Box 25, Folder 256)
    - Spain, 1926-1929 1926-1933 (Box 25, Folder 257-258)
    - Vignaud, Jean Henry, 1911-1922 (Box 25, Folder 259)
    - Miscellaneous, 1921-1943, undated (Box 26, Folder 260-262)
- Writings, 1907-1941; Series II; 6; (14 boxes)
  This series contains files arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Alonso de Chaves, [ca. 1930s-1940s]
    - Chapters I-III; XII-XVIII (Box 27, Folder 263-264)
    - Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 265)
    - Drafts (Box 27, Folder 266)
    - Manuscript and research material (Box 27, Folder 267-268)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 269)
    - Photostats of original text (Box 28, Folder 270-271)
    - Typescripts (Box 28, Folder 272-273)
  - Atlas of Portolan Charts, [ca. 1911]
    - Facsimile (Box 29, Folder 274)
    - Manuscripts (Box 29, Folder 275-276)
    - Notes (Box 29, Folder 277-279)
    - Proofs and typescripts (Box 29, Folder 280-282)
    - Typescripts (Box 29, Folder 283-284)
  - William Janszoon Blaeu, [ca. 1914]
    - Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 285-286)
    - Proofs (Box 29, Folder 287)
    - Typescript and notes (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - Cabot, [ca. 1941]
    - Manuscripts and notes (Box 30, Folder 289-291)
  - Caneiro Map Text, [ca. 1908]
    - Proofs (Box 30, Folder 292)
  - Casa de la Contratacion, [ca. 1927]
    - Manuscripts and references (Box 30, Folder 293)
  - Christopher Columbus and His Enterprise, [ca. 1913]
    - Manuscripts (Box 30, Folder 294-295)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 296)
    - Typescript (Box 30, Folder 297)
  - Early Spanish Cartography, [ca. 1909]
    - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 298)
    - Proofs (Box 31, Folder 299)
    - Reprints (Box 31, Folder 300-301)
  - Genoese World Map, [ca. 1912]
    - Proofs (Box 31, Folder 302)
    - Typescript (Box 31, Folder 303)
  - Geography of Ptolemy, [ca. 1931]
    - Book I; dedication (Box 32, Folder 304-306)
    - Book II-Book VII (Box 32, Folder 307-317)
    - Introduction and correspondence (Box 32, Folder 318)
    - Miscellaneous pages of text (Box 33, Folder 319)
    - Notes (Box 33, Folder 320-322)
    - Photostats (Box 33, Folder 323)
    - Proofs (Box 33, Folder 324-326)
    - Reviews (Box 33, Folder 327-328)
    - Translation (Box 34, Folder 329)
    - Typescripts (Box 34, Folder 330-333)
  - Map of The World by Jodocus Hondius, [ca. 1907]
    - Correspondence and notes (Box 34, Folder 334)
    - Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 335)
    - Typescript (Box 34, Folder 336)
  - Marine World Chart of Nicolo de Caneiro Januensis, [ca. 1908]
    - Miscellaneous typescripts (Box 34, Folder 337)
    - Proofs (Box 34, Folder 338)
      General
      See also: box 30, folder 292
  - Terrestial and Celestial Globes, [ca. 1921]
    - Bibliographies and lists (Box 35, Folder 339-340)
    - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 341-342)
    - Illustrations (Box 35, Folder 343-344)
    - Manuscripts (Box 35, Folder 345-346)
    - Manuscripts (Box 36, Folder 347-350)
    - Notes (Box 37, Folder 351)
    - Proofs (Box 37, Folder 352)
    - Typescripts (Box 37, Folder 353-354)
- Subject Files, 1870-1941; Series III; 5; (12 boxes)
  This series contains files arranged in the following sections: Addresses and Lectures, Book Reviews, Personal Papers, Printed Material, Manuscripts, Notes, Outlines, Student Papers, and Miscellanea.
  - Addresses and Lectures
    - "Recent advances in astronomical science", 1922 (Box 38, Folder 355)
    - "The Building of a Nation", undated (Box 38, Folder 356)
    - California lectures, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 357)
    - "Chronology and the Calendars of Various Times", undated (Box 38, Folder 358)
    - Dante, undated (Box 38, Folder 359)
    - "Early Cartography of the New World and Its Value for the Student of the Period" (Box 38, Folder 360)
    - "Early Spanish Cartography of the New World - The Padron Real", [1909?] (Box 38, Folder 361)
    - European history, undated (Box 38, Folder 362-363)
    - Franklin College address, 1914 (Box 38, Folder 364)
    - French history, undated (Box 38, Folder 365-367)
    - French Revolution, undated (Box 38, Folder 368)
    - "Real and Imaginary Geographical Conditions... ", [ca. 1919-1928] (Box 38, Folder 369)
      See also box 46, folder 482
    - "Geography of Ancient Greece", undated (Box 38, Folder 370)
    - "Geography of the Renaissance Period...", 1904 (Box 38, Folder 371)
    - German humanism, undated (Box 38, Folder 372)
    - Highways, undated (Box 38, Folder 373)
      See also: box 46, folder 487
    - Historical geography, 1917, undated (Box 38, Folder 374-375)
    - Historical geography of ancient Egypt, undated (Box 38, Folder 376)
    - Humanism in the 15th century, undated (Box 38, Folder 377)
    - International Geographical Congress address, 1925 (Box 39, Folder 378)
    - Johns Hopkins University lectures, 1904 (Box 39, Folder 379)
      See also: box 38, folder 371
    - Maritime geography, undated (Box 39, Folder 380)
    - Martin Waldseemuller and early cartography, [ca. 1904] (Box 39, Folder 381)
    - Medieval mapmakers, undated (Box 39, Folder 382)
    - Nationality, undated (Box 39, Folder 383)
    - Oceanography, undated (Box 39, Folder 384)
    - "Physical Features of the Earth as a Home for Man", undated (Box 39, Folder 385)
    - Reformation, undated (Box 39, Folder 386)
    - Renaissance, undated (Box 40, Folder 387)
    - "The Rhineland and its Romances", undated (Box 40, Folder 388)
    - "Spanish Civilization.. .", 1936 (Box 40, Folder 389)
    - Spanish history, undated (Box 40, Folder 390)
    - "Time and Its Measurements.. .", 1934 (Box 40, Folder 391)
    - "The Wide Diffusion of Wealth Among the 1926 People.. ." (Box 40, Folder 392)
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1879-1934] (Box 40, Folder 393-394)
  - Book Reviews
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1906-1920] (Box 41, Folder 395-396)
  - Personal Papers
    - Coats of arms, undated (Box 41, Folder 397)
    - Diary as a student at Franklin College, 1880 (Box 41, Folder 398)
    - Facsimile of illuminated Persian manuscript, undated (Box 41, Folder 399)
    - Franklin College articles, 1881-1882, 1912, undated (Box 41, Folder 400)
    - Harrington, Admiral P.F., 1922-1937 (Box 41, Folder 401)
    - List of publications, 1929-1939 (Box 41, Folder 402)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 41, Folder 403)
    - Parr, Harry L., 1940 (Box 41, Folder 404)
    - Photographs: unidentified, undated (Box 41, Folder 405)
    - Rutgers College, 1907-1908, undated (Box 41, Folder 406-407)
    - Soviet Trans-Polar Fliers Dinner, 1937 (Box 41, Folder 408)
    - Student essays, 1897 (Box 41, Folder 409)
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1880-1940] (Box 41, Folder 410)
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1885-1936] (Box 42, Folder 411-114)
  - Printed Material
    - Announcements, [ca. 1905-1921] (Box 42, Folder 415)
    - Association of American Geographers: Annals, 1927, 1933 (Box 42, Folder 416)
    - Clippings of notices, 1917-1928 (Box 42, Folder 417)
    - "Maps Illustrating the Discovery and Exploration of America, 1502-1530", 1903 (Box 42, Folder 418)
    - Notices, 1907-1941 (Box 43, Folder 419-420)
    - Publications, undated (Box 43, Folder 421-422)
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1870-1930] (Box 43, Folder 423)
  - Manuscripts
    - "Archeological Discoveries in The Western Hemisphere", 1926 (Box 43, Folder 424)
    - Astrological constellations, undated (Box 43, Folder 425)
    - "Brief Description of the Atlas Signed Nicolas de Dieppe", undated (Box 43, Folder 426)
    - "The Causes and Cure of Lawlessness", undated (Box 43, Folder 427)
    - Columbus, undated (Box 43, Folder 428)
    - Constellations, [ca. 1931] (Box 43, Folder 429)
    - "Derrotero of the Coast of the South Sea", undated (Box 43, Folder 430)
    - "Descriptive List of Maps Reproduced as Glass Transparencies", 1909, 1912 (Box 43, Folder 431)
    - "Early Spanish Cartography of the New World", undated (Box 43, Folder 432)
    - Drama manuscript-historical account, undated (Box 44, Folder 433)
    - Egypt, 1928 (Box 44, Folder 434)
    - "Geographical Activities of the Casa de Contratacion", undated (Box 44, Folder 435)
    - Geographical expansion, undated (Box 44, Folder 436)
    - "The Spirit of German Humanism", undated (Box 44, Folder 437)
    - "The Goths - Their Origin and Their Ethnological Relations", undated (Box 44, Folder 438)
    - "Growth of English Constitution", undated (Box 44, Folder 439)
    - "Historical Values at Jamestown", undated (Box 44, Folder 440)
    - "How the Discovery of the New World became Known to the Old", undated (Box 44, Folder 441)
    - Humanism in Germany and Italy - incomplete, undated (Box 44, Folder 442)
    - Individuals, undated
      - Albuquerque, Affonso (Box 44, Folder 443)
      - Almagro, Diego de (Box 44, Folder 444)
      - Avila, Pedro Arias de (Box 44, Folder 445)
      - Ayllon, Lucas Vasquez de (Box 44, Folder 446)
      - Bastedas, Roderick de (Box 44, Folder 447)
      - Behaim, Martin (Box 44, Folder 448)
      - Bobadilla, Francisco de (Box 44, Folder 449)
      - Cabral, Pedro Alvarez (Box 44, Folder 450)
      - Columbus, Christopher (Box 44, Folder 451)
      - Coronado (Box 44, Folder 452)
      - Corte-Real, Gaspar (Box 44, Folder 453)
      - Cortes, Fernando (Box 44, Folder 454)
      - Davila, Gil Gonzales (Box 44, Folder 455)
      - Gama, Vasco da (Box 44, Folder 456)
      - Garay, Francisco (Box 44, Folder 457)
      - Gomez, Esteban (Box 44, Folder 458)
      - LaCosa, Juan de (Box 44, Folder 459)
      - Leon, Ponce de (Box 44, Folder 460)
      - Magellan, Ferdinand (Box 45, Folder 461)
      - Martyr, Peter (Box 45, Folder 462)
      - Narvaez, Panfilo de (Box 45, Folder 463)
      - Nicuesa, Diego de (Box 45, Folder 464)
      - Nino, Per Alonso (Box 45, Folder 465)
      - Ojeda, Alonso de (Box 45, Folder 466)
      - Pigafetta, Antonio (Box 45, Folder 467)
      - Pinzon, Martin Alonso (Box 45, Folder 468)
      - Pizarro (Box 45, Folder 469)
      - Soto, Hernando de (Box 45, Folder 470)
      - Vespucci, Amerigo (Box 45, Folder 471)
    - "In Jackson's Day", undated (Box 45, Folder 472)
    - "Jefferson and Morris in France during …the Revolution", undated (Box 45, Folder 473)
    - "Marine World Map of…Caneiro", 1907 (Box 45, Folder 474)
    - Middle Ages, undated (Box 45, Folder 475)
    - "The New Columbus", undated (Box 45, Folder 476)
    - New World Geography - chapters 8-11, undated (Box 45, Folder 477)
    - "The Travels of Nicolo Conti in the East", undated (Box 45, Folder 478)
    - Padron Real, undated (Box 45, Folder 479)
    - "Progress of Geographical Knowledge in Middle Ages and the Renaissance", undated (Box 45, Folder 480)
    - Ptolemy, [ca. 1938] (Box 45, Folder 481)
    - "Real and Imaginary Geographical Conditions…", 1919 (Box 46, Folder 482)
    - "Recent Archeological Discoveries in Egypt", 1932 (Box 46, Folder 483)
    - The Reformation, Karl Meyer, undated (Box 46, Folder 484-485)
    - Renaissance history, undated (Box 46, Folder 486)
    - "Roads and Highways" Kittredge, undated (Box 46, Folder 487)
    - Ruysch map, undated (Box 46, Folder 488)
    - "Social Life in the days of the Meistersingers", 1894 (Box 46, Folder 489)
    - "A Summer's Vacation in the Old World", undated (Box 46, Folder 490)
    - "Wanderings of Plants and Animals", 1924 (Box 46, Folder 491)
    - Miscellaneous, unidentified and incomplete, undated (Box 46, Folder 492)
    - Miscellaneous, unidentified and incomplete, undated (Box 47, Folder 493-494)
  - Notes, [ca. 1880s-1930s]
    - Albuquerque - Vespucci (Box 47, Folder 495)
    - Cartographers and geographers (Box 47, Folder 496-497)
    - European and American history (Box 47, Folder 498)
    - Explorers and mapmakers (Box 47, Folder 499)
    - Geography (Box 47, Folder 500)
    - Geography lectures (Box 47, Folder 501)
    - History courses (Box 48, Folder 502)
    - Invention of printing (Box 48, Folder 503)
    - Lecture notes - miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 504)
    - Medieval manuscripts (Box 48, Folder 505)